Bissonette mss., 1855-1862 LMC 1090
Lilly Library
Bissonette mss.
1855-1862
Lilly Library
Bissonette, Joseph, active 1860
LMC 1090
1 folio
The Bissonette mss., 1855-1862, consist of letters and documents primarily of Joseph Bissonette, trader and frontiersman, from Nebraska Territory, relating to claims for losses incurred from depredations committed by the Indians.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Acquisition Information
Gift: 1946
Biographical Note
Joseph Bissonette was born into a family of explorers in the French region of what is now East St. Louis, Illinois, on 26 May 1814. In the 1840s, he joined Colonel John C. Fremont's expeditions exploring the Rocky Mountains and was an interpreter for Chief Red Cloud. By the 1860s, he had moved to the Nebraska Territory, near Fort Laramie, where he worked as a trader. He eventually moved to the Pine Ridge Indian Reservation and died in Oglala Lakota County, South Dakota, in August 1894.
Scope and Content Note
The Bissonette mss., 1855-1862, are letters and documents primarily of Joseph Bissonette, trader and frontiersman, from Nebraska Territory, relating to claims for losses incurred from depredations committed by the Indians.
Americana; Indians of North America --Claims against.; West (U.S.); Bissonette, Joseph; Greenwood, Alfred Burton, 1811-1889.; Manypenny, George Washington, 1809-1893.; Caruthers, Samuel, 1820-1860.; Harney, William S. (William Selby), 1800-1889.
- Manuscript materials, 1855-1862
  - Letter from Joseph Bissonette to the Government of the United States, Jan. 15, 1855 (Foliobox 2)
  - Letter from George W. Manypenny to Samuel Caruthers, Apr. 16, 1856 (Foliobox 2)
  - Joseph Bissonette giving power of attorney to Joseph C. R. Clark to represent him in his claims against the Office of Indian Affairs, Dec. 15, 1860 (Foliobox 2)
  - Joseph Bissonette. Agreement to give Joseph C. R. Clark part of his claim as payment for his services, Dec. 19, 1860 (Foliobox 2)
  - Joseph Bissonette and John Richard giving power of attorney to Joseph C. R. Clark to represent them in their claims against the Office of Indian Affairs, Dec. 21, 1860 (Foliobox 2)
  - Charles Lajeness? Power of attorney to Joseph C. R. Clark to represent him in his claims against the Office of Indian Affairs, Dec. 21, 1860 (Foliobox 2)
  - John Richard. Power of attorney to Joseph C. R. Clark to represent him in his claims against the Office of Indian Affairs, Dec. 21, 1860 (Foliobox 2)
  - Francis V. Tagon. Power of attorney to Joseph C. R. Clark to represent him in his claims against the Office of Indian Affairs, Dec. 22, 1860 (Foliobox 2)
  - Letter from A.B. Greenwood to Joseph C. R. Clark, Mar. 2, 1861 (Foliobox 2)
  - Louis Guinard. Promissory note to Thomas S. Tarss?, Aug. 18, 1862 (Foliobox 2)